musicradio.com 2019-12-25

# privacy - Global

**  1.     What is in this policy?**

This policy tells you:

·       what information we might collect about you

·       how we might use that information

·       when we might use your details to contact you

·       what information of yours we might share with others

·       your rights about the personal information you give us

**2.      Who are we?**

We are Global, the Media & Entertainment group. Global is Europe’s largest radio company home to some of the biggest brands in commercial radio, namely Capital, Heart, LBC, Classic FM, Smooth, Capital XTRA and Gold.  Our portfolio also includes our digital platform PopBuzz, our outdoor advertising companies and our licensed broadcast partners, Communicorp and Quidem. Any personal information that you provide to us may be shared across our brands and platforms (e.g websites or apps) and may be used in the ways described in this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy explains how we collect and use information about you when you interact with our radio, digital brands, outdoor advertising and this website.

Our services sometimes link to services or adverts run by other companies. These take you away from a Global website or brand app, and these companies have their own privacy and cookie policies. Please remember you should know that we have no control over the content or privacy practices of those other platforms and that the information you give them will follow their policies and rules and not ours.  We advise you to check their privacy policies before providing your information to them.

**3.           What personal information do we collect?**

The information we may collect about you will vary depending on how you interact and engage with us. It may include the following:

a.    General identification and contact information

We may collect your name, address, phone number, email address, IP address, user name, password, age, gender, date of birth.

b.    Financial information

We may collect your name, bank account and sort code. For example, if we need to pay you for winning a competition.

c.     Sensitive information

We may collect your racial or ethic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, sex life or sexual orientation. e.g. radio discussions or survey answers you have chosen to provide on radio may indicate or tell us such information.

d.    Device information

We may collect some technical information from devices (e.g. computer, mobile, TV, tablet, speaker or other voice-enabled devices) and web browsers. This might include IP address, device ID. We will uniquely identify each instance of that use.

e.     Marketing preferences

We may collect information if you access our services or programmes such as how you use our services and the articles you read

f.      Information if you communicate with any of our stations or website

If you call, text, email or otherwise communicate with us, we may collect your name, location and a brief summary of your contribution or opinion. Please note this may include sensitive information (e.g. political opinion, trade union) as above

g.    Location information

When you first use our App, you will be asked if we can use your location in order to offer you services and information that is relevant to your area. We will also have information regarding your general geographic location based on your IP address and the GPS of your mobile device.

h.     Information on your activities outside Global services when you comment on Global

We will not normally collect any sensitive personal information from you (unless you provide it to us as above), and will, in any event, ask for your express consent to hold this information if we need to do so.

Please do not submit such personal information or sensitive information if you do not wish us to collect it.

**4.      What information do we collect about you from other sources?**

We may obtain additional information about you from trusted third parties and public sources:

a.    to assist us in our marketing, including Online Behavioural Advertising, and to ensure that you receive adverts and other information that is relevant to you, For example, when you have entered a competition or completed a survey/questionnaire and have agreed that this data may then be shared with others including Global. This information may include details about our users’ demographics, interests and classifications and be used to place users in particular groups or segments for targeting advertising. Some of this information may also have come from publicly available sources.

Please be aware that if you log in via Facebook or Twitter you will be giving Facebook and Twitter permission to share some of your details with us depending on your privacy settings on their site. For example, if your Facebook privacy settings are set to allow it, they will provide us with your public profile which includes your name, profile picture, emails address, age range, gender, language spoken and gender.

**5.      How do we use your Personal Information?**

We have to have a valid reason to use your personal information. This is called a “lawful basis for processing”. We process personal information for the following legal basis:

a.     Consent

We use your personal data if we have your consent. We rely on consent for the following:

–        to enable you to login to your account

–        to enable you to enter and process winners for competitions on our platforms (e.g. radio stations, websites)

–        to tell you about products, events, services and promotions that we or our third party partners are offering

–        to answer you when you have contacted us, or to respond to a comment or complaint

–        for marketing purposes

–        to send you notifications on your device if you have selected them

You have the right to withdraw consent at any time. Where consent is the only legal basis for processing, we will cease to process data after consent is withdrawn.

b.     The processing is necessary to fulfil a contract

We may process your data when we need to fulfil a contract with you.

c.     Legitimate Interest

We process your data when it is in our legitimate interest to do this and when these interests are not overridden by your data protection rights.

Our legitimate interests include:

–        to improve our content, products, services and customer experiences by monitoring your use of our services and working with our suppliers to improve the products and services we offer, develop new content and services

–        to create profiles for targeted advertising and marketing opportunities

–        to show adverts to the people most likely to be interested in the products and services being promoted

–        to ensure the security and integrity of our services

–        to ensure that our Websites and Apps operate effectively

–        to protect customers and other individuals and maintain their safety, health and welfare

–        for market research

–        to deal with your requests, complaints and enquiries

We will use your information to deliver targeted advertising to you when you visit our websites. This is known as online behavioural advertising (OBA). It works by giving you adverts based on the way you have interacted with the website. For example, if you have been clicking on articles about pop music, you may be shown more adverts for live pop music events. None of the OBA techniques used will collect personal information such as your name, email address, postal address or phone number. If you would like more information regarding OBA and how to opt out, please visit http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/

d.     Necessary to comply with a legal and regulatory obligations

We may process your personal information to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations e.g. preventing, investigating and detecting crime, fraud or anti-social behaviour and complying with law enforcement agencies.

**6.      Who do we share your personal information with?**

a.     Our group companies

We may share your personal data with certain members of our group companies. Where they have access to your personal information they will use it only for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy.

b.     Partners

If you sign up for one of our partnered services, such as online dating, you will be providing your information directly to our third party partner. We advise that you check their privacy policy or statement to understand how they use your information.  They may share certain information with us, which we will only use for the reasons set out in this policy and this will not include sensitive personal information or financial information.

c.     Sponsors

If you enter a competition, we may, if you have agreed, disclose your information to the competition sponsors. If you are a prize winner, we will give your information to the sponsors and share your information with the parties who assist us in providing prizes to the winners.

We may carry out research or analysis, which contains your personal information, via our sites, and share aggregated responses to questions with our partner organisations.

d.     Our service providers

We may share your personal data with our external third-party service providers.

These include accountants, auditors, lawyers, other professional advisors, IT systems, support and hosting service providers, printing, advertising, marketing, market research and analysis service providers, website analytics and online behavioural advertising providers, technical engineers, data storage and cloud providers and similar third party vendors and outsources service providers that assist us in carrying out business activities.

e.     Government authorities and third parties

f.      Other third parties

**7.      Personal Information relating to children and minors**

Our services are not directed towards individuals under the age of 18.

We do not knowingly use or process the personal information of children under 13 years of age either directly or indirectly.

**8.      How long do we keep your information for?**

We hold personal data for different purposes and the length of time we keep your information will vary depending on the services or products we are providing. We will only keep your data for a reasonable period of time, which is based on the purpose for which we are using your data. Once that purpose has been fulfilled, we will securely delete that data or anonymise your information (so that we, or anyone else, can no longer tell that data relates to you) unless we are required to retain the data longer for legal, tax or accounting reasons.

To determine the period we store personal data, we always stick to these principles:

–        we will only keep your information for as long as we need to

–        we think about what type of information it is, the amount collected, how sensitive or intrusive it might be and any legal requirements

we design our services so that we do not hold your personal information longer than we have to.

**9.      International Transfers of Personal Information**

Personal information which you supply to us is generally stored and kept inside the European Economic Area.

However, due to the nature of our business and the technologies required, your personal information may be transferred to a third party service provider outside the EEA. These countries may not have the same data protection laws, including a lower level of protection.

If we do need to transfer your personal information in this way we take steps to ensure your level of privacy including data minimisation, anonymising or pseudonymising data, undertaking due diligence on the recipients and putting in place contractual obligations on them to take care of your data, for example EU model clauses, or in the case of US recipients, a Privacy Shield certification.

**10.   Your rights in relation to how we use your personal information.**

Data Protection laws give you certain rights in respect of your personal information. You have the following rights:

·       Right to rectification

The right to have your personal data corrected if it is inaccurate or incomplete. You can also manage some of this yourself if you have registered with us via one or more of our websites.

·       Right of access

You have the right to obtain your personal data from us. This is referred to as a data subject access request.

·       Right to be erasure (“right to be forgotten”)

You have the right to be forgotten.

·       Right to object and opt-out of marketing

You have the right to object to the processing of your personal data. This includes the right to object to direct marketing. You will always be given the opportunity to opt-out of further direct marketing when you receive such communications from us or you can contact us at crm.marketing@global.com

·       Right to portability

You have the right to move, copy or transfer certain personal information

·       Right to restrict processing

You have the right to restrict the use of your information in certain circumstances

·       Right to opt-out of automated individual decision-making (including “profiling”)

You have the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which significantly affects you or produces legal effects.

If you wish to submit a request in relation to any of your rights above, please contact us at: privacy@global.com.  Please note you will be asked to supply us with proof of identity before we will be able to provide you with a response

**11.   Contact Us and Complaints**

The data controller responsible for your personal information is Global Media & Entertainment Limited.

If you do have any concerns we would like you give us the opportunity to know about them so we would encourage you to contact us first so we can try and to help you: privacy@global.com or write to the Data Manager, Global Media, 30 Leicester Square London WC2H 7LA.

If you do not think we are handling your personal information adequately, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office. Further information, including contact details, are available at ico.org.uk.

**12.   Changes to Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy will be amended from time to time if we make any important changes in the way that we collect, store and use personal data. We will notify you where required.
